# KEHINDESALAUDEEN

## FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Lagos Nigeria | kehindesalaudeen222@gmail.com | +234 805 649 9531 https://github.com/kenicodex | https://khenny-portfolio.netlify.app https://www.linkedin.com/in/kehnydev/

## PROFILE SUMMARY

Detail-oriented and qualified Frontend Developer able to collaborate with a team, 3+ years experience with JavaScript libraries React, jQuery, and Bootstrap, able to work in an agile scrum environment. I help companies like Matrizo, Devken, and Lagos State Polytechnic build client-side web applications and to translate UI/UX wireframes (like Figma) for company and customer needs into functional, user-friendly, and appealing interactive applications.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### FrontEnd Developer

# Matrizo Codtrix | Remote

Jan, 2022 - Present

- Proposed 5 UI and UX design changes which lead to 30% increase in technical feasibility
- Developed program logic with React for new application conversion based on existing html application which enhanced user experience and functionality by 20%.
- Designed several reusable components which reduced production time by 1 week for the team

## Freelance Fullstack Developer

April, 2019 - Present

#### DevKen | Remote

- Develop well-functioning RESTful API in Nodejs and manage databases
- Design scalable React frontend applications from wireframes UI/UX
- Test software to ensure responsiveness and efficiency

#### **Frontend Engineer**

May 2021 - Oct 2021

## Lagos State Polytechnic ICT | Lagos

- Worked well with different developers to address challenges and solve problems collaboratively on the organization's website
- Tested web-based product functionality and delivered iterations to customers in the sprint method

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Computer Science BSc**

2018 - 2022

#### Caleb University, Lagos

- Graduated in top 15% of 150+ dass with 4.6 CGPA in a 5 points system
- Volunteer tutor for students who were interested in web development

## PROFESSIONAL SKILL

## ADDITIONAL SKILL

React Javascript Nextjs Angular & Vue HTML & CSS Scrum Nodejs RESTful API